# Selvasarukesh K

selvasarukesh-portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode Email: selvasarukesh.k@gmail.com | Mobile: 91 6384066040

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

I am a skilled web developer with over **2.5 years of experience** in **Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PL/SQL**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Angular, and SpringBoot** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Java , HTML, CSS , TypeScript ,PL/SQL

**Frameworks** : Angular, Spring, SpringBoot

**Databases** : Oracle, PostgreSQL

**Dev Tools** : Git, Gitlab, Docker, Power BI, RedHat OpenShift, Jenkins

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Executive - Software Development**

Jun 2024 - Present

Location: Pune, Maharastra, India

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Pune

- Managed the design, development, and maintenance of payment gateways and mandates .
- Worked on **cloud migration** to enhance user experience.
- Acquired extensive experience managing multiple applications in a dynamic IT environment.

## **Graduate Trainee - Software Development**

Jun 2024 – Jun 2024

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Pune

• Collaborated on the development and enhancement of multiple real-time insurance applications using **Angular**, **Java**, and **Spring Boot** frameworks.

## **Intern - Software Development**

Sep 2022 - Jun 2023

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Coimbatore

 Acquired hands-on experience in IT real-time culture and advanced technologies through a comprehensive internship program.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Application**

8.20 GPA

Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya College of Arts and Science - Coimbatore

Jun 2020 - Jun 2023

## **Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)**

72.83 GPA

Syed Ammal Metric Hr Sec School - Ramanathapuram

Jun 2019 - May 2020

## **PROJECTS**

### **Payment Gateway and Mandate**

Angular, Spring Boot, Oracle, Javascript, Git

Source Code

- Designed and developed a Optimized website for a seamless **customer experience** and implemented real-time mandates with a clean workflow.
- Ensured seamless and efficient service delivery through **cloud** integration.

## **BloodSecure Management**

Angular, Spring Boot, PostgresSQL, Git

Source Code

• We allow users to register their blood details and for administrators or other users to locate nearby donors in emergency situations.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certified Java Developer by Coding Ninja
- Certified in Java Spring Framework 6 with Spring Boot 3 Udemy
- Certified Java Developer by Spoken Tutorial